In terms of applications,
在应用方面
ICA is widely used in medical scanners.
独立成分分析广泛应用于医学扫描仪
And so, this is an example of a type of brain scan called the EEG or MEG,
这是一个叫做 EEG 或 MEG 的脑部扫描仪的例子
where each of these sensors detects
这些传感器检测脑内电讯号
electric signals or in a similar test magnetic signals inside the brain.
或脑内相似检验磁信号
And so each of these is you know the electric sensor and each of them would produce
这些都是传感器 每一个都会产生
these readings that are all mixtures of things happening inside the brain.
脑内活动的混合读数
And so ICA can be used where these are the initial or actual readings of this data.
如果这些数据是最初或真实读数 就可以利用独立成分分析
ICA is an algorithm that's able to look at them and then find the independent components
这种算法可以感受到并找到脑内产生
inside the brain that generated these readings and where, that are mixed here.
这些混在一起的读数的独立成分
Because an electric signal would be generating when one part of the brain would bounce,
因为当大脑的一部分弹跳时 就会产生电讯号
would be hard to tell because you have the skull separating
这很难分辨 因为颅骨隔开了
the sensors from the actual places.
传感器和产生信号的实际区域
So ICA is widely used in scenarios like this.
所以独立成分分析广泛应用于此类情境下
It's also used in FMRIs the same way for a lot of brain scans.
同样的 它还大量用于脑部扫描的扫描机
So these are the independent components and it can isolate
这些是独立成分 它可以分离
where certain signals came from in the brain.
脑内传来某些信号的区域
There have been attempts at using ICA for financial data.
已经有人尝试在财务数据中运用独立成分分析
I don't know that this is a very popular thing to do,
我知道这样做是不是很普遍
but it's just interesting to look at I guess.
但我认为了解一下也很有趣
And so this is one paper that tries to apply ICA to a factor model in finance let's say.
这篇论文尝试将独立成分分析应用于金融中的因子模型
So this data is stocks, stock signals.
该数据为股票 股票信号
And it tries to isolate what caused the stocks to go up and down,
它试着分离出是什么引起股票波动
what components are there.
这里有什么成分
And most of these papers that are trying to do ICA in finance, something like this.
大部分这些论文尝试在金融中进行独立成分分析 就像这样
The economy is completely,
经济完全是一个非常
is a very complex system and so they rarely would come up with
复杂的系统 所以很少得到
things that are of deep need, of real value.
有强烈需求或实际价值的东西
It just could be interesting to look at, I guess.
只是研究起来比较趣
There's another one looking at financial data as well.
这一个也观察了金融数据
And so this is a data set of five stores and this is the cash flow of them.
这是一个五家商店的数据集 这是它们的现金流
So there's a chain,
这就存在一个链条
a retail chain of some sort.
某种零售链条
And so this is the cash flow over 140 weeks.
这是超过 140 周的现金流
And so you see spikes that go up and they go down.
你可以发现峰值起起伏伏
To make it a little bit more clear, let's break it down.
为了看得更清楚 我们来进行分解
So this is the first year,
那么这是第一年
this is the second year,
这是第二年
and this is a part of the third year that is available.
这是第三年可获取的部分
So you can see dip here,
你可以看到下降
or spike and then a dip.
或增加然后下降
This is about Christmastime I guess.
我猜这跟圣诞节有关
So if we do ICA to this,
所以 如果我们对其进行独立成分分析
we get these four components.
我们得到这四个成分
And they would give some indication of things that are happening.
它们会给出一些正在发生的事情的迹象
So this first component captures this rise,
第一个成分捕捉到了该上升现象
the spike and dip in Christmas for example.
比如是圣诞节的起伏
And this fourth one captures the,
第四个捕捉到的是
during the summer month there seems to be a bit of a slump here.
夏季月份看上去有些下跌
So this is another thing that I thought is interesting to look at.
这又是一件我认为看起来很有趣的事情
There aren't a lot of papers or applications of using ICA
我们没有许多在金融数据中应用独立成分分析的论文或应用
in a financial data but it could be intriguing.
但这类研究也很有趣